<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div id="backup">
    <h1>Backup policy</h1>
    <div>(under development) </div>
    <h2>Source backup</h2>
    <div>A descriptor file defines all code and other resources. This file is used by an export
        script to both view the resouces and their descriptions, and to zip the resources up. The
        zip file is stored in /var/www/backups.  An export should be run before changes to code. The
        link to the resources is in /admin </div>
    <div>only the last backup is stored on this server- backup elsewhere for longer periodseg using
        wget </div>
    <div>Restore from this backup requires unzipping the archive locally and selectively restoring
        scripts or data. </div>
    <div>There is a case for using the eXist packaging facility here. </div>
    <h2>Corpus data backup</h2>
    <div>There is a corpus-specific resource file for each corpus which is used to zip up the corpus
        data files in the same way. This backup can be done after each major update to the corpus
        and then stored off-server.</div>
    <h2>Full file level backup</h2>
    <div>The admin panel supports manual backup, either full or incremental. The resultant backup
        can be downloaded via the path {host}:8080/exist/admin/backups/{version}.zip . The files are
        stored in the filestore in directory $EXIST_HOME/webapp/WEB-INF/data/export </div>
    <div>Automated backups could be done using cron and the $EXIST_HOME/bin/backup.sh script </div>
    <div>see exist-org for explanation of the restore</div>
    <h2>Low-level backup</h2>
    <div>2.0 has a lowlevel backup of the raw database files  . This zips the
        raw database files and stores in $EXIST_HOME/webapp/WEB-INF/data/backups. </div>
    <div>A restore requires saving the current files in the $EXIST_HOME/webapp/WEB-INF/data
        directory, finding a suitable backup to restore, unzipping the backup file into the data
        directory and restarting. [at present this is an undocumented feature of 2.0 and there
        should be scripts to do this - not sure what happens to the fs (binary file) directory in
        this] </div>
    <h2>Server backup</h2>
    <div>Should be configured on ElasticHosts VPS</div>
</div>