<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div id="rulesets">
    <h1>Rulesets</h1>
    <h2>Introduction</h2>
    <div>In this prototype, the original <a href="http://data.aidinfolabs.org/?type=rule&amp;mode=view">set of rules</a> used in the production version for activity validation have been
        improved: <ul>
            <li>Compliance rules which applied to the whole document have been refined and now may
                apply to any sequence of nodes</li>
            <li>Rules may also define a precondition. </li>
            <li>Validation rules have been reformated and split into <a href="/data/ruleset">multiple
                    rulesets</a> which fulfil different purposes</li>
            <li>One or more rulesets can be selected when validating an activity.</li>
            <li>Rule behaviour has been generalised and is defined in a generic XQuery module
                (rules.xqm)</li>
            <li>A ruleset may be created for any document so organisation documents can be validated
                in the same way.</li>
        </ul>
    </div>
    <h2>Ruleset structure</h2>
    <div>
        <table border="1">
            <tr>
                <th>Ruleset properties</th>
                <td>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>@name</th>
                            <td>Unique ruleset name</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>@version</th>
                            <td>To align with the IATIStandard version</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>@xml:lang</th>
                            <td>Language code - only English descriptions are in used</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>@root</th>
                            <td>The root element for these rules</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>description</th>
                            <td>An html fragment to describe the purpose of the ruleset.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th>Rule properties</th>
                <td>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>path</th>
                            <td>required</td>
                            <td>an absolute or relative path. Paths ending in * are applied at to
                                the sequence of nodes, otherwise the path defines a node</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>pre</th>
                            <td>optional</td>
                            <td>an XPath expression which determines if the rule should be applied *</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>codelist</th>
                            <td>optional</td>
                            <td>the name of an IATI codelist against which a node value is to be
                                checked</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>type</th>
                            <td>optional</td>
                            <td>the XPath name of a type, for example xs:date</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>assertion</th>
                            <td>optional</td>
                            <td>the XQuery expression to be evaluated to determine if the node
                                passes the rule.*</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>description</th>
                            <td>required for assertions, optional otherwise</td>
                            <td>A natural language description of the rule, especially of the
                                pre-condition and assertion. This is expressed in the same sense as
                                the rule. If the rule fails, this condition will not be met </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th>* Context variables</th>
                <td>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>$doc</th>
                            <td>Bound to the whole document (iati-activity)</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>$this</th>
                            <td>Bound to the node(s) identified by the path</td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                </td>
            </tr>
        </table>
    </div>
    <h2>Background</h2>
    <div>The IATI standard is defined in terms of an <a href="http://www.w3.org/XML/Schema">XML
            schema</a> + additional rules described in words in documents. Rules in addition to
        those implicit in the XML schema are needed : <ul>
            <li>To avoid imposing an ordering on elements, the XML schema has to be lax, and is thus
                unable to express constraints on the cardinality of elements, for example that an
                activity requires a title. </li>
            <li>External codelists are used extensively in the specification and, unless these are
                included in the XML schema, the values of codes cannot be validated</li>
            <li>Rules such as the requirement that percentages sum to 100 cannot be expressed in XML
                Schema. Neither can rules which are conditional on the value of other elements in
                the document </li>
        </ul>
    </div>
    <div>Furthermore, some rules depend on the usage to which the activity data is to be put e.g.
        the requirement for sector data if sector analysis is to be performed. This leads to the
        view that validation is relative to need rather than being an absolute condition. For
        example, in order for a publisher to develop their publishing process, the completeness of
        the data will depend on the stage in development. </div>
    <div>Other schema languages such as <a href="http://www.schematron.com/">Schematron</a> and the
        future XML Schema Version 2.0 improve the ability of the schema language to express
        constraints. However the reporting of errors and the availability of an error analysis so
        that the validation of multiple activities can be combined and assessed depends on external
        schema engines. It may be possible to switch to a different schema language in future, but
        in order to make progress, a local rule-based approach using XQuery was adopted for this
        project. </div>
    <div>The current approach uses a set of rules which are applied during a top-down traverse of
        the document (iati-activity) so that rule violations can be notified as close as possible to
        the offending element or attribute. The rule-based approach makes composition of rules
        possible although processing speed may suffer.</div>
    <h2>Work to do</h2>
    <ul>
        <li>The current rule definition goes most of the way to providing an XML format for the
            spreadsheet version of the IATI Standard document and could be expanded to meet this
            need.</li>
        <li>Rulesets, especially the Standard set, need full checking</li>
        <li>Some compliance rules may be difficult to format into this framework </li>
        <li>Rules may need parameterisation - eg to specify the length of a title or periods for
            planned-disbursement. This could be done with the addition of a parameter group but
            perhaps versioning a ruleset may be adequate. </li>
        <li>distinction between rules applied to a node and rules applied to a sequence is clumsy and needs adjustment</li>
    </ul>
</div>